<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<posts>
  <row Id="1" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="24" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:09:32.720" Score="49" ViewCount="3016" Body="&lt;p&gt;I just got a pound of microroasted, local coffee and am curious what the optimal way to store it is (what temperature, humidity, etc)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastActivityDate="2019-02-04T13:15:48.970" Title="How should I store whole bean coffee?" Tags="&lt;storage&gt;&lt;whole-bean&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="2" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="22" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:13:58.610" Score="7" ViewCount="1163" Body="&lt;p&gt;I manually grind coffee beans for drip coffee but I thought that depending on whether the coffee is intended to be used for a cafetiere or espresso machine then the fineness needs to be varied.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So what is the optimum fineness for drip coffee?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does it matter so much given that I am not using pressure (typically 15 bar in an espresso machine) to force hot water through the coffee grounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastEditorUserId="8" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T21:13:20.537" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:13:20.537" Title="How fine should I grind coffee for drip/pour over coffee" Tags="&lt;ground-coffee&gt;&lt;drip-brew&gt;&lt;pour-over&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="3" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="15" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:20:05.700" Score="30" ViewCount="1677" Body="&lt;p&gt;I live in a hard water area and when brewing English Tea I can &lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; taste and see the difference when compared to where I'm from, which is a soft water area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the hardness of the water matter when making coffee, too?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance, whether or not the taste is more or less intense depending on the hardness of the water. I haven't noticed but I would think it does affect the flavor.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'd be interested in a &lt;strong&gt;scientific/objective view&lt;/strong&gt;. As of now, I use bottled water in my kettle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastEditorUserId="262" LastEditDate="2016-05-02T01:36:46.847" LastActivityDate="2019-11-28T09:51:33.867" Title="Does the hardness of water matter when making coffee?" Tags="&lt;flavor&gt;&lt;brewing-process&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="4" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="37" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:30:33.657" Score="10" ViewCount="335" Body="&lt;p&gt;I own a drip coffee pot:&#xA;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/H0sqP.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and one of the other things you can buy is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hario.jp/product/list.php?middelclass=3&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;thin spouted kettle&lt;/a&gt; which is used for pouring water one to the grounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is the theory behind this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does the rate of water delivery/flow just agitate the suspension of coffee/water in a way that is better?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I also see such items being used in coffee shops too so would really like an expert's summation on this.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastEditorUserId="8" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T21:26:01.250" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:58:54.353" Title="What's the theory behind using thin spouted kettles when making drip/pour over coffee" Tags="&lt;drip-brew&gt;&lt;pour-over&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="8" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="5" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="8" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:34:58.077" Score="21" ViewCount="1319" Body="&lt;p&gt;I observe that coffee servers (I refuse to use the term barista) will apply pressure to the coffee grounds using a variety of methods and pressure. This seems to vary wildly and I'd like to know how important is this? Is there some general rule of thumb when it comes to recommended pressure?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My thoughts were that the fineness mattered the most for espresso machines and that reasonable enough pressure when tamping is enough but what do expert's use and believe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastEditorUserId="8" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T20:46:23.583" LastActivityDate="2022-02-24T19:13:05.100" Title="How important is tamping coffee for an espresso machine" Tags="&lt;espresso-machine&gt;&lt;tamping&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="6" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="11" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:39:34.113" Score="41" ViewCount="43217" Body="&lt;p&gt;The rule of thumb is that you first drink coffee approximately 3 days after it is roasted, but what is the exact reason for this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="16" LastEditorUserId="86" LastEditDate="2016-09-15T09:49:15.433" LastActivityDate="2021-05-14T00:49:05.183" Title="Why is it not recommended to drink coffee immediately after it's roasted?" Tags="&lt;roasting&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="7" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="5" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:46:43.660" Score="18" Body="&lt;p&gt;Tamping is one of three key controls you have over the espresso brewing process; The others are dose (the amount of coffee used) and grind coarseness.  Together, they allow the coffee machine operator to produce a puck of the correct density and consistency through which the pressurized water can be pushed through.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While techniques vary, the &quot;rule of thumb&quot; is to apply roughly thirty pounds of force evenly across the puck; however, the key is consistency.  Keep your variables the consistent and you'll be able to dial in the best end-product.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I've been able to pull great shots using anything from just the weight of the tamper itself to my full weight pushed onto a puck, keeping all of the other factors where they needed to be to create the correct puck density.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See this video below for more detail: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wholelattelove.com/community/videos/1854/quick-tip-what-is-the-right-way-to-tamp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;What is the Right Way to Tamp?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastEditorUserId="2751" LastEditDate="2016-07-12T18:50:36.753" LastActivityDate="2016-07-12T18:50:36.753" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="8" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="5" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:50:57.833" Score="15" Body="&lt;p&gt;Let's start off with what the function of the tamp is.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/xt7gz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Function&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tamp is cylindrical in shape and is ideally just snug enough to fit into the portafilter smoothly. What the tamp does, is prime the coffee bed to be met with water. What we know about the water is that in general, in commercial machines, water is applied with 9 bars of pressure. Physics tells us that pressured water flow will take the path of least resistance. By this logic, the tamp functions by making the coffee bed smooth, even, and robust enough to be hit with 9 bars of pressure and extract evenly. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Barista Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: In no way am I a qualified physician. This is not to be considered medical advice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If the surface one tamps on is on the proper level, the barista should be able to tamp with their elbo at a 90 degree(ish) angle, and their wrists in a semi-straight path to prevent damage. The barista can then use their body weight, and not muscle, to perform the tamp. By leaning into the tamp with the correct path, one can achieve about 30lbs of pressure. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Experiments with varying pressure&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Personally I have experimented with varying pressured tamps and have found that applying a greater pressure than 30 lbs produced little effect, at most, a longer extraction. There are other variables that should be adjusted instead, such as the grind size, to achieve such an effect.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T20:50:57.833" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="9" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:53:01.987" Score="11" ViewCount="2122" Body="&lt;p&gt;For a given coffee and roasting method, what factors of the espresso making process affect the crema and in what way(s) do they affect it? By my own empirical evidence, I would guess that time since grinding, coarseness of the grind, and tamping pressure are the biggest factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastActivityDate="2018-09-18T09:38:15.227" Title="What factors affect espresso crema?" Tags="&lt;espresso&gt;&lt;crema&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="10" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="23" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:55:37.073" Score="10" ViewCount="421" Body="&lt;p&gt;I notice that some barista's keep whacking the doser on the coffee grinder when they fill the espresso holder. What's the theory behind this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would've thought that the fact that the coffee is being ground and falling into the holder that it is being aerated enough already so why do this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This may be something to do with specific grinder models, it may be just the lever to release coffee, I don't know but would like to hear from someone who knows better than me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="8" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:13:24.420" Title="Why do barista's keep activating the doser whilst grinding coffee" Tags="&lt;espresso-machine&gt;&lt;grinder&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="11" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:56:11.087" Score="30" Body="&lt;p&gt;Fresh off the roast, coffee has high levels of carbon dioxide and nitrogen (based?) gasses. These gasses will greatly contribute to &lt;em&gt;retro-nasal activity&lt;/em&gt; as well as initial flavors (think carbonated water). The most apparent flavor one gets from this is &lt;em&gt;metallic&lt;/em&gt;. At my work, 4 days is considered minimum for serving and tasting, although there's always exceptions. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T20:56:11.087" CommentCount="9" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="12" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="18" CreationDate="2015-01-27T20:59:25.627" Score="15" ViewCount="1502" Body="&lt;p&gt;I came across &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffee.stackexchange.com/q/1/19&quot;&gt;this question&lt;/a&gt;, which seeks the optimal method for storing whole beans. In that same vein, I'd like to know the best way to store ground coffee to preserve freshness. Should ambient temperature and humidity be considered?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="19" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:51:53.733" LastActivityDate="2017-08-10T11:21:57.687" Title="How should I store ground coffee?" Tags="&lt;storage&gt;&lt;ground-coffee&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="3" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="13" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="19" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:00:21.060" Score="10" ViewCount="298" Body="&lt;p&gt;I ground some coffee beans this morning, but I'm not a major coffee drinker, how fast can I expect its flavour to degrade, and at what point would it become completely undrinkable?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="25" LastActivityDate="2019-05-03T13:23:46.573" Title="How long can I store ground coffee in the fridge?" Tags="&lt;storage&gt;&lt;ground-coffee&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="14" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="46" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:02:09.410" Score="28" ViewCount="4023" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've heard of adding salt to coffee to reduce its bitterness.&#xA;I've also heard that using freshly roasted and ground coffee would reduce the bitterness experienced when drinking coffee. Though it seems making freshly roasted coffee could actually make things worse, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffee.stackexchange.com/questions/6/why-is-it-not-recommended-to-drink-coffee-immediately-after-its-roasted&quot;&gt;this question&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is there a documented process (not additive) to reduce the bitterness of coffee and any research in why that's the case?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="22" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:51:53.733" LastActivityDate="2016-09-16T20:01:47.713" Title="What is the process to reduce bitterness in coffee?" Tags="&lt;flavor&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="15" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="3" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:03:42.773" Score="23" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That is to say it will definitely affect flavor, but how it affects the flavor is ultimately dependent upon the specific mineral compounds found in your hard water vs. other hard waters and soft water's lack of these compounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here's the key: Some of the compounds in hard water are &amp;quot;sticky,&amp;quot; glomming onto certain compounds in coffee when they meet (in your coffeemaker). The more eugenol the water hangs on to, for example, the woodsier the taste of your coffee will be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Magnesium is particularly sticky, meaning water that's high in magnesium will make coffee with a stronger flavor (and higher levels of caffeine). Hard water can also have high levels of bicarbonate, though, which Hendon found could lead to more bitter flavors coming through.  - A Chemist Has Uncovered A Secret To Brewing Delicious Coffee At Home &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/a-chemist-has-uncovered-a-secret-to-delicious-coffee-2014-6#ixzz3Q3ecJSgz&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Business Insider&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So depending on flavor preferences you might prefer your hard water at home but dislike it at work or simply prefer soft water altogether. Traditionally hard water is actually sought after for other beverage processes like beer brewing because of some of the abilities described above.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2020-06-18T08:36:22.093" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:03:42.773" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="16" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="33" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:03:46.707" Score="16" ViewCount="5177" Body="&lt;p&gt;Many methods of brewing coffee differ in the temperature of the water among other factors. Some people swear by cold-brewing, others do slow pour overs with piping hot water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How exactly is coffee flavor changed by cold, warm, and hot water?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="5272" LastEditDate="2018-04-03T12:22:41.767" LastActivityDate="2018-04-03T12:22:41.767" Title="How does the temperature of the water affect the taste of the coffee" Tags="&lt;brewing-process&gt;&lt;cold-brew&gt;&lt;temperature&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="17" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="9" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:04:31.483" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espresso#crema&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;The &quot;crema&quot; is produced by emulsifying the oils in the ground coffee into a colloid, which does not occur in other brewing methods. &#xA;  &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/UK772.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Using the right material from the start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Personally, I think this definition could use some updating. Crema exists because of the freshness of the coffee, in relation to it's roast. It contains the gasses we find from roasting, such as carbon dioxide and nitrogen gasses. You will notice that if you dig up coffee that is months old and brew it as espresso, there will be little crema. Bottoml ine, if you want crema, you need fresh coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;Extraction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other factor in producing crema, is correct extraction. If you have a poorly extracted shot of espresso, it will be primarily water, with some seriously over-extracted coffee. An even extraction will produce the highest yield of crema.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:04:31.483" CommentCount="8" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="18" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="12" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:07:08.867" Score="11" Body="&lt;p&gt;In general, it's best to &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; store ground coffee. If quality really matters, then the real answer is to back up. Try to grind only enough coffee for what you're using immediately to brew with. If you're buying preground coffee, then storage and optimal quality become somewhat trivial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once the surface area of the coffee is increased (by grinding it), the majority of the coffee is exposed to air, accelerates the decomposition of the coffee, meaning it likely isn't going to stay fresh for long anyway. Think of it like opening a dry, red wine. Since it's been opened, it's going to turn faster than it being left in the bottle because it's been exposed to atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So in short, if flavor and freshness really matter, try not to &lt;em&gt;store&lt;/em&gt; ground coffee if at all possible.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you really &lt;strong&gt;must&lt;/strong&gt; store ground coffee, keep it sealed airtight. The exposure to atmosphere is going to be the strongest catalyst in making your coffee less than fresh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastEditorUserId="4" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T21:12:48.687" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:12:48.687" CommentCount="5" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="19" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="13" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:08:27.040" Score="15" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coffee should never be stored in the fridge!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the same way that &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sodium_bicarbonate#Applications&quot;&gt;baking soda&lt;/a&gt; absorbs smells, coffee will absorb smells and flavors in your refrigerator. These compounds can be extracted when you brew your coffee and will contribute to undesired flavors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proper storage of coffee is to put your beans into an airtight container, and store around 25C out of sunlight (EX: your cabinet). &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:08:27.040" CommentCount="6" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="21" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:12:16.330" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;In general, the coarseness of fine sand. It will be difficult to effectively communicate grind size here, and what is recommended is to go to your local coffee shop, have them grind a sample of coffee for you on their drip grind, and then have you take that home and calibrating your grinder to a similar size, adjusting for taste.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:12:16.330" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="22" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="2" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:12:35.147" Score="7" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In general consistency is more important than a specific setting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The key is that you can actually control both the size of the grind and actually achieve a homogenous grind allowing you to increase the consistency in the coffee when you brew it as you can assertively control the service area being exposed during the brewing process. Since you stated that you have a burr grinder you are off to a great start. There is no defined, agreed upon coarseness of grind for pour over coffee, but I would definitely say that you would want a courser grind than you would for espresso. Experiment to find the sweet spot by making sure you use exactly the same water, coffee bean roast, and number of beans (and thus volume) between different grind settings to find what meets your flavor best. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you are particularly worried about &quot;getting it right&quot; or do not want to do a ton of experimentation an easy and quick way to jump to a grid would simply to go to a coffee shop, buy a bag of whole beans, ask them to grind it and query them for how coarse of a grind is. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:12:35.147" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="23" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="10" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:13:24.420" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short reason:&lt;/strong&gt; Tradition conflicting with modern brewing practices.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long reason:&lt;/strong&gt; This is more a result of an industry-wide legacy when purchasing equipment, where coffee shop owners will pick up mechanically dosed grinders instead of doserless, or electrically metered models because &quot;that's how it's been done,&quot; or because the technology simply wasn't  affordable until simple microcontrollers became cheap. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Traditionally,&lt;/em&gt; you would grind enough coffee to fill the doser, dispensing grounds for brewing as needed and refilling the doser when the level dropped too low.  Dosers exist to allow for predictably size quantities of grounds to be dispensed into the portafilter, and that's basically it.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This, however, conflicts with the &quot;Third Wave&quot; coffee culture, where flavor and texture are paramount.  In this new culture, coffee beans are ground for immediate use, rather than drawing from a bin.  The moment beans are ground, the gasses contained within (gasses that are the reason Crema exist) are allowed every opportunity to escape.  The longer they sit, the less gasses will be left behind by the time they're used to brew.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So when a Third Wave coffee shop grinds using a doser, the Barista rapid-fires the dosing lever, essentially moving the coffee straight into the portafilter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A better plan is just to use a direct-dosing grinder where the grounds are metered by time or weight straight into the filter.  Advances in the packaging options for load cell sensors and simple controllers have made this somewhat common in both consumer and commercial equipment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="26" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:13:24.420" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="24" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:17:34.843" Score="46" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a cool, dark, dry, place and whenever possible vacuum sealed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The oils in roasted coffee degrade as they are exposed to air (oxidization) as well as heat. As with just about any foodstuff moisture accelerates the spoiling process as well. You should store your coffee in completely sealed, insulated, opaque containers. If you have the ability, vacuum pump the air out of the container for ultimate shelf-stability. Even without vacuum storage you can preserve beans for a long time by placing them inside a ziplock bag or coffee bag with a 1-way air seal and pushing as much air out as possible and then following the above method of airtight, dark and cool storage. Following these guidelines should help to ensure the freshness and flavor of the beans for as long as possible. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="24" LastEditDate="2015-12-24T18:51:22.207" LastActivityDate="2015-12-24T18:51:22.207" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="25" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="267" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:17:51.653" Score="6" ViewCount="119" Body="&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to create a cleaning agent to use on a basic drip coffee maker using household items? If so, what ingredients are needed and in what ratios? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am mostly concerned with cleaning the insides that I believe are made from plastic. The carafe I can clean separately. I know that there are products on the market, but I am interested in homemade solutions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="23" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T17:05:03.993" LastActivityDate="2015-01-30T17:37:38.737" Title="homemade cleaner for basic drip coffee maker" Tags="&lt;cleaning&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="8" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="26" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:18:15.860" Score="6" ViewCount="129" Body="&lt;p&gt;In my, somewhat limited, experience with espresso machines they generally only produce a few shots of espresso per load. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is this a technical limitation of espresso making or is it just that the manufactures expect normal, healthy, people to only drink a shot or two at a time?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To put it another way:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Are there machines out there that are capable of producing a pot of espresso or does the process require small batches?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastActivityDate="2022-11-17T02:04:11.717" Title="Upward size limit for espresso makers" Tags="&lt;espresso-machine&gt;&lt;brewing-process&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="27" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="26" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:22:44.583" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;The volume of espresso that your machine makes, is limited to the size of it's boiler and it's ability to replenish, heat the water, and deliver the force to brew the espresso. Working on commercial machines, I've seen boilers last 5+ minutes before losing temperature. With such a machine, your coffee would probably run out of desirable flavor before you'd make a full &lt;em&gt;pot&lt;/em&gt; of espresso.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="17" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:22:44.583" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="28" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="32" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:23:20.747" Score="6" ViewCount="128" Body="&lt;p&gt;I switched from a modestly priced blade grinder to a moderately priced cone grinder because the results were inconsistent  (some very fine powder and some only fragmented beans mixed with usable grounds).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Will I have more consistency and control if I switch to a high-end cone grinder? I'm thinking about a refurbished restaurant grade grinder, not an industrial grade machine as one might find at a Starbucks or boutique roaster.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="34" LastEditorUserId="24" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T21:29:25.863" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T02:58:36.360" Title="Are high-end cone grinders adjustable?" Tags="&lt;grinder&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="29" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="34" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:27:09.077" Score="16" ViewCount="2554" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm aiming to reduce my caffeine intake, but don't want to drop coffee altogether. What roasts / beans release the least amount of caffeine into my body when drank?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="25" LastActivityDate="2019-05-12T22:42:53.797" Title="What type of roast has the lowest caffeine content?" Tags="&lt;roasting&gt;&lt;caffeine&gt;&lt;beans&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="30" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="26" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:29:26.020" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;The key here is &lt;em&gt;extraction&lt;/em&gt; from the espresso coffee. Only so much desirable flavor and body can be pulled from a puck of coffee. So, then you might say, why not make the puck bigger? Well then that would force the water through a thicker puck, causing the extraction to be slower and longer, giving bitter flavors. The amount of pressure needed to make a desirable &quot;pot of espresso&quot; with a larger &quot;puck&quot; (or probably more accurately, a &quot;slab&quot; in this case) would be a wild safety hazard, since the pressure would be too immense for any cost-effective equipment to handle. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, is it a technical limitation? Yes and no. I think it has more to do with being a tried process that gives repeatable, scientific results. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:29:26.020" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="31" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="28" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:30:30.067" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What you describe as a conical grinder is also known as a burr grinder. Burr grinders are important because they allow you to create ground coffee that is both homogenous and set to a specific granular size/coarseness.  This is a key feature and selling point of these grinders and it easily allows the user to grind for espresso one moment and drip coffee the next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:30:30.067" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="32" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="28" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:33:04.337" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;Yes, high end grinders are generally adjustable. Some even have macro and micro adjustments. For example the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.baratza.com/flat-burr-grinders/vario-grinder/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Baratza Vario grinder&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hand grinders are also adjustable, and provide a good grind. See the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hario.jp/coffee/grinder.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Hario range&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The larger commercial grinders are sometimes aimed more at bulk output than at a precise and consistent grind. They grind the coffee very quickly, which may not be the quality you are looking for. Some people prefer grinders that operate at a lower speed so that the temperature of the burrs stays low, reducing the chance of the grind getting over roasted&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gearpatrol.com/2013/02/25/grind-it-out-10-best-coffee-grinders/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Here's a list&lt;/a&gt; of mid to high end grinders. You will notice that they all have adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastEditorUserId="39" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T00:03:33.897" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T00:03:33.897" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="33" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="16" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:35:46.843" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Temperature affects extraction rate, but also varies between compounds in the coffee beans.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coffee grounds contain a hodgepodge of volatile and non-volatile components, such as various oils, acids, and other aromatic molecules [2]. Collectively, these compounds that are found in coffee grounds are referred to as “coffee solubles” and significantly contribute to coffee flavor [2]. Brewing is the process of extracting these components from the grounds, so coffee beverages are technically a solution of coffee solubles and water. Given that coffee grounds are used in both of our brewing methods, the principle variables are temperature and time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Temperature affects the solubility and volatility of the coffee solubles. Relative to brewing, solubility describes the ability of the solubles to dissolve out of the grounds and into the water; volatility refers to their ability to evaporate into the air. Coffee solubles dissolve best at an optimal temperature of 195-205°F [3]. With more coffee solubles extracted, hot brew coffees are described as more full-bodied and flavorful when compared to cold brew. Moreover, due to increased volatility with higher temperatures, the aromatics are more readily released from coffee, giving rise to that beloved scent of freshly-brewed coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the downside, oxidation and degradation also occur more rapidly at higher temperatures. The oils in coffee solubles can oxidize more quickly at elevated temperatures, causing coffee to taste sour. Acids also degrade, the most notable of which is chlorogenic acid into quinic and caffeic acid, causing coffee to taste bitter [2].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Where cold brew lacks in temperature, it makes up for in time. Coffee solubles have markedly decreased solubility in room temperature water. Increasing the brew time from a few minutes to many hours aims to maximize extraction of the solubles from the grounds. Even over twenty-four hours, not all the coffee solubles will have dissolved; this is why the amount of coffee grounds is doubled, in an effort to make up for the lower extraction rate. In comparison with hot brew, cold brew is sometimes described as tasting “dead” or “flat” due to the lower yield of coffee solubles [3]. Further, decreased volatility prevents aromatics from escaping from coffee as easily, so cold brew is much less perfumed than its hot brew counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oxidation and degradation will still occur in cold brew methods, but this happens much more slowly; bitterness and acidity are just about absent in cold brew coffee, especially if it is kept cold. Though, cold brew doesn’t merely taste like hot brew without the bitterness. Fans of the cold brew method have emphasized that cold brews contain a completely different flavor profile that can’t be found with hot brews. Going back to the idea of solubility, not all flavor compounds of coffee solubles are equally soluble. A good majority of the coffee solubles are still able to leach out of the grounds, even in colder water. The compounds that don’t dissolve are the ones often attributed to unfavorable flavors [4]: these stay in the grounds that are subsequently tossed away. Consequently, cold brews take on a much sweeter, floral profile.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To note, brew time does not determine caffeine content, nor does bitterness indicate coffee strength. Caffeine is extracted early in the brewing process, so extending brew time, by either method, would only result in over-extracted coffee [1]. Coffee “strength” is defined as the amount of dissolved coffee solubles per unit of coffee volume [1]. On that train of thought, cold brew certainly produces stronger coffee, given that the brewing process purposely concentrates the coffee solubles. Though, keep in mind that rarely anyone drinks cold brew coffee straight up; many enjoy this smooth drink diluted with milk or water. - &lt;a href=&quot;https://scienceandfooducla.wordpress.com/2014/08/19/coffee-brewing-chemistry-hot-brew-and-cold-brew/&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Coffee Brewing Chemistry: Hot Brew vs. Cold Brew.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2020-06-18T08:36:22.093" LastActivityDate="2016-10-06T19:02:17.430" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="34" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="29" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:38:40.710" Score="15" Body="&lt;p&gt;In general, &lt;strong&gt;darker, arabica&lt;/strong&gt; roasts have less caffeine. Arabica (as opposed to robusta) inherently has less caffeine in it naturally, and darker coffees have less caffeine since they have been roasted longer or at higher temperatures, &lt;strike&gt;essentially &quot;burning&quot; the caffeine out of the bean.&#xA;&lt;/strike&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For some science, Arabica is usually found to be about 1.2% caffeine and Robusta is typically 2.2% caffeine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;http://coffeechemistry.com/agriculture/differences-between-arabica-and-robusta-coffee.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Differences between Arabica and Robusta Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chris in AK has a great explanation in the comments as to why darker roasts are &lt;em&gt;perceived&lt;/em&gt; to have less caffeine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;It is a common misconception that darker roasts have less caffeine.  Caffeine's melting point is 455F which is well above what most beans reach during the roasting process.  Essentially, caffeine content changes because the mass/density of the beans change (they lose water and undergo changes in the roasting process).   If you measure your coffee by volume, dense greener beans will have more caffeine.  If you measure by weight, darker roasted beans will have more caffeine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastEditorUserId="2751" LastEditDate="2016-09-15T09:49:20.317" LastActivityDate="2016-09-15T09:49:20.317" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="35" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="14" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:50:40.847" Score="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;Bitterness comes from over-extracting coffee. Over-extraction is mainly caused by:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1) brewing for too long: In the beginning of the brewing stage acidic flavors are first extracted, followed by sweetness.  And towards the end of the brew, only bitter flavors are extracted.  The trick is to stop the brewing just after all the sweetness is extracted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From Wikipedia: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coffee_extraction#Extraction_yield&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Coffee extraction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Yields of under 18% are &quot;under-extracted&quot;, specifically&#xA;  &quot;under-developed&quot; – desirable components have not been sufficiently&#xA;  extracted – and &quot;unbalanced&quot;, specifically sour, because acids are&#xA;  extracted early, while balancing sugars (sweetness) and bitter&#xA;  components are extracted later. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;  &#xA;  &lt;p&gt;Yields of over 22% are &quot;over-extracted&quot;, specifically bitter, as&#xA;  bitter components continue to be extracted after acids and sugars have&#xA;  largely completed extraction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2) Grind size being to small: small grind size means larger total surface area of the particles.  Therefore, flavors get extracted more quickly and can lead to over-extraction. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The optimal brew time and grind size vary depending on the method (french press, manual pour, espresso etc..), and you'll need to experiment to get it just right.  The type of coffee bean also matters, but probably to a lesser degree than the above two factors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="42" LastEditorUserId="2751" LastEditDate="2016-09-16T20:01:47.713" LastActivityDate="2016-09-16T20:01:47.713" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="36" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:52:59.630" Score="10" ViewCount="388" Body="&lt;p&gt;I just recently purchased an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wholelattelove.com/products/ecm-technika-iv-espresso-machine&quot;&gt;ECM Technika&lt;/a&gt; and have noticed recently that my shots have been fairly inconsistent. A friend suggested that I backflush the machine, but didn't have a chance to explain to me exactly &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do that. Can anyone tell me how to backflush my machine? How often should I do this? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastActivityDate="2020-12-09T17:01:39.720" Title="How do I backflush my espresso machine?" Tags="&lt;maintenance&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="37" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="4" CreationDate="2015-01-27T21:58:54.353" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;By having a thin spout, you can more finely control the flow rate and where the water lands.    When making pour-over coffee, you want to control the water level in the cone to control the brew time and evenly extract coffee.  Also, water needs to be poured carefully onto the middle of the cone so that the water doesn't run down the side of the cone without touching the coffee grounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="42" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T21:58:54.353" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="38" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:03:02.643" Score="10" ViewCount="268" Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't have a coffee press so I just brew ground coffee as you would tea: in the cup. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How hot should be the water to brew with this method? Should it be boiling, or a lower temperature?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="user48" LastEditorUserId="4" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T22:08:44.997" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:24:09.617" Title="How hot should water be to brew ground coffee directly in a cup?" Tags="&lt;ground-coffee&gt;&lt;brewing-process&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="39" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="41" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:07:46.300" Score="35" ViewCount="5247" Body="&lt;p&gt;When I bought my aeropress, it came with this weird hexagon thingy: &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/Q99VV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hexagon thingy&quot; title=&quot;aeropress funnel&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is it for? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastEditorUserId="8" LastEditDate="2015-01-29T19:44:56.720" LastActivityDate="2015-07-17T14:24:30.953" Title="What is the hexagon funnel shaped thing that came with my aeropress for?" Tags="&lt;aeropress&gt;&lt;identify-this&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="41" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="39" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:08:50.447" Score="47" Body="&lt;p&gt;It took me an embarrassingly long time to realize the purpose of this hexagon shaped funnel, so I am sharing this via a self posted answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hexagon funnel has three purposes:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a funnel to make it easier to pour your ground coffee into the aeropress opening. &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/mrCWj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;funnel for putting ground coffee into aeropress&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a funnel for cups with a small opening at the top. The image shows a shot-glass as an example. Trying to use an aeropress with a cup that is too small sucks. &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/UfXeI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;as a funnel for small cups&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a stand, so when your aeropress is stowed, it all neatly stacks together. &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/75JHQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;stacked aeropress&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="39" LastEditorUserId="39" LastEditDate="2015-07-17T14:24:30.953" LastActivityDate="2015-07-17T14:24:30.953" CommentCount="6" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="42" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="38" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:11:07.213" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm no expert, but a frequent enjoyer, and I also use freshly ground coffee in a cup, then pour water over it. &lt;strong&gt;I always go with boiling water and have never heard of any reason to change.&lt;/strong&gt; My coffee tastes great too, so I think I'm doing it right.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the way, in my country (Sweden) we call that a 'Turkish' brew.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="52" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:11:07.213" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="43" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:11:21.803" Score="10" ViewCount="288" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm recently drinking a lot of coffee at work. I'm worried about the health issues - lost of calcium from the bones.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;How can I prevent calcium loss? Drinking coffee with milk is out of option for me - I'm lactose intolerant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="user48" LastActivityDate="2015-01-29T22:30:05.193" Title="How to prevent calcium loss when drinking a lot of coffee?" Tags="&lt;health&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="3" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="44" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:15:06.293" Score="11" ViewCount="26777" Body="&lt;p&gt;The coffee package I've bought has 'strength rating'. It's 3 out of 5. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I wonder what that 'strength' means? How it is measured? Does it relate to the caffeine amount?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The coffee package is from Germany, and from what I've seen, all coffee sorts have this rating, so it's a kind of standard.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="user48" LastEditorUserId="3" LastEditDate="2015-01-27T22:30:19.307" LastActivityDate="2020-01-31T10:16:02.103" Title="What does the 'strength' mean (in numbers)?" Tags="&lt;rating&gt;&lt;strength&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="45" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="38" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:15:19.220" Score="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;Your method most closely resembles &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_coffee&quot;&gt;Turkish Coffee&lt;/a&gt;, which is suggested to be served at hot, &lt;strong&gt;but not boiling&lt;/strong&gt; temperatures. Since the exposure to the grounds is so direct, it's easy to burn the coffee at boiling temperatures. You want a full body, but not a burnt taste (yuck!) &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.turkishcoffeeworld.com/How-to-make-Turkish-Coffee-s/54.htm&quot;&gt;Turkish Coffee World&lt;/a&gt; recommends about 158 degrees Fahrenheit or 70 degrees Celsius.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:15:19.220" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="46" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="14" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:18:54.370" Score="19" Body="&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of factors that contribute to the bitterness of coffee. Some of these have to do with the concentration of various compounds in the coffee and the roasting process, but the way you brew the coffee can make a big difference as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Assuming that you are not going to be harvesting and roasting your own coffee, we can focus on the brewing process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Beans:&lt;/strong&gt; Robusta vs Arabica&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To decrease perceived bitterness in coffee, the best choice is Arabica. Arabica beans are often sweeter with notes of sugars and fruits and a somewhat wine-like acidity. Robusta on the other hand tends to be harsher with more bitterness. This difference in quality is reflected in cost however, as Arabica tends to be more expensive than Robusta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In terms of roast level, medium roasts generally contain fewer soluble solids, more acidity and a stronger aroma than dark roasts. All of these should contribute to making medium roasts on average less bitter than dark roasts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water&lt;/strong&gt;: Temperature and Chemistry&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You have to find the sweet spot when it comes to temperature, a little trial and error can be used here depending on the blend and brewing method. For example, the people at AeroPress recommend a much lower temperature to reduce bitterness that what you would use in a french press.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In general research has shown that coffee brewed in hot water is perceived to be less bitter than when cold water is used. Additionally, bitterness is reduced when hard or soft water is used when compared to distilled water.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brewing [Extraction]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bitterness is strongly correlated with the amount of dissolved solids in the brewed coffee. To ensure that the amount of dissolved solids and the overall extraction is correct (and minimally bitter), make sure to use the correct grind coarseness, water temperature, and brew time for your chosen method. Over extraction can be a major cause of bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Drip and pour-over brewing methods tend to have less bitterness than a french press or other immersion methods. This can be attributed to less dissolved solids in the coffee. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SCIENCE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Much of this section will be outside the control of most, but it is interesting nonetheless. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Research has found that the introduction of polyphenols reduces the bitterness of coffee. The metallic bitterness found in some coffee has been attributed to  dicaffeoylquinic acids. Trigonelline is perceived as bitter at concentrations of 0.25% and its degredation is proportional to roast level. Roasting Trigonelline produces a byproduct called pyridines and helps create the roasty aroma found in some coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chlorogenic acid is also found in coffee, higher concentrations in Robusta than Arabica, and that contributes to the bitterness as well. Additionally, Quinic acid is a product formed from the degradation of Chlorogenic acid and is present in coffee at twenty times its taste threshold, contributing to the bitterness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furfuryl alcohol is also known to increase the bitterness of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coffeeresearch.org/science/bittermain.htm&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Coffee Chemistry: Cause of Bitter Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekitchn.com/coffee-basics-the-difference-b-41949&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Coffee Basics: The Difference Between Arabica and Robusta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="38" LastEditorUserId="2751" LastEditDate="2016-09-15T09:49:10.320" LastActivityDate="2016-09-15T09:49:10.320" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="48" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="57" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:20:11.957" Score="13" ViewCount="3484" Body="&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my question should be &quot;What is the best type of grinder to use at my desk if I work in a cubicle and use a French Press?&quot;. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have tried finding decibel measurements on Amazon's website, but most of the coffee grinders listed don't specify them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="44" LastActivityDate="2020-01-05T11:50:54.590" Title="Which type of coffee grinder is the quietest?" Tags="&lt;grinder&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="3" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="49" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="48" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:22:40.400" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;A manual coffee grinder like the &quot;Hario Ceramic Coffee Mill&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:22:40.400" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="50" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="38" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:24:09.617" Score="0" Body="&lt;p&gt;I go with around 165 degrees Fahrenheight (73 C).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:24:09.617" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="51" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="48" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:30:48.523" Score="6" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wholelattelove.com&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;WholeLatteLove.com&lt;/a&gt; actually provides decibel ratings for many of their coffee grinders such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wholelattelove.com/products/mazzer-mini-electronic-type-a-coffee-grinder&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Mazzer Mini&lt;/a&gt;. Perhaps you could compare some grinders there.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="4" LastEditorUserId="4" LastEditDate="2015-12-03T06:03:50.980" LastActivityDate="2015-12-03T06:03:50.980" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="52" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:31:05.283" Score="7" ViewCount="3880" Body="&lt;p&gt;Coffee flavor is often described in terms of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roast darkness (light to dark)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Body (medium to heavy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acidity (smooth to bright)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have a vague understanding of some of these, but am unclear especially on body. Could someone explain these a bit and show how they differ from one another?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastActivityDate="2021-11-28T18:23:24.783" Title="Roast vs Body vs Acidity" Tags="&lt;flavor&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="53" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="80" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:33:51.377" Score="12" ViewCount="2810" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've heard that the V60 is better for light roasts and the Aeropress is better for Medium to Dark roasts, but could someone describe how these two brewing devices affect the flavor of coffee brewed for the different roasts (and which, in turn, would be preferable)?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="54" LastActivityDate="2015-07-03T00:53:30.150" Title="How V60 and Aeropress affect flavor" Tags="&lt;flavor&gt;&lt;aeropress&gt;&lt;v60&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="54" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="77" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:33:56.587" Score="7" ViewCount="480" Body="&lt;p&gt;I often find that some methods of brewing for a particular implement differ on whether or not to stir the grounds at some point in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I understand that stirring while brewing should increase the extraction, but when and why would I use stirring to do it instead of a finer grind, longer brew, higher temp, etc?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="58" LastEditorUserId="5272" LastEditDate="2018-04-07T23:59:48.837" LastActivityDate="2018-04-07T23:59:48.837" Title="When to use stirring to increase extraction?" Tags="&lt;brewing-process&gt;&lt;extraction&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="55" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="36" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:34:14.187" Score="10" Body="&lt;p&gt;Backflushing is a fairly straightforward procedure. You only need &lt;strong&gt;two&lt;/strong&gt; things:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.co.uk/imgres?imgurl=http://i.ebayimg.com/00/s/MTE1NFgxNjAw/z/fZIAAOxy6MBSSlAz/%2524T2eC16F,!zkFJCOFBk,kBSSl!ys6z!~~60_35.JPG&amp;amp;imgrefurl=http://www.ebay.com/itm/STAINLESS-STEEL-BLIND-FILTER-BACKFLUSH-DISK-/271641948190&amp;amp;h=216&amp;amp;w=300&amp;amp;tbnid=ynq9S5wUZeePwM:&amp;amp;zoom=1&amp;amp;docid=e99XOeBEvG5xzM&amp;amp;itg=1&amp;amp;ei=KhHIVISeIJTnaoXWgfgH&amp;amp;tbm=isch&amp;amp;ved=0CCwQMygLMAs&quot;&gt;backflushing disc&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;coffee machine &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.greenbeanery.ca/bean/catalog/images/Cafiza_20oz.jpg&quot;&gt;detergent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The procedure needs repeating a few times (3-4):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Install the disc in the portafilter &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in a bit of cleaning detergent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn on the coffee machine until you hear the pump start to labour, once this happens turn the pump off, and the hot water with detergent will spray out of your 3-way valve. This is quite likely to cause &lt;strong&gt;spraying&lt;/strong&gt; so try to be careful.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After you've done this, repeat the procedure without detergent to flush the soap suds from the machine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Normally you would do this &lt;strong&gt;about once a month&lt;/strong&gt;. This is highly dependant on how you feel the machine is doing, but it's definitely recommended that you do this if you use the machine a lot (Some people recommend doing it around every 30th espresso).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After this it is a good idea to run one espresso shot through the machine to clear everything out and not leave any residue.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find further details &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.home-barista.com/espresso-machine-cleaning.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="57" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:34:14.187" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="56" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="64" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:36:12.250" Score="23" ViewCount="976" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am a heavy coffee user and I want to know what's in my coffee and therefore I'd like to grow coffee in my home.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to grow coffee in an apartment?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="65" LastActivityDate="2018-07-18T09:22:22.483" Title="How to grow coffee at home?" Tags="&lt;growing&gt;&lt;farming&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="7" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="57" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="48" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:36:32.920" Score="15" Body="&lt;p&gt;First, lets ignore blade grinders entirely.  Any grinder that doesn't have a motor will be relatively quiet.  You'll be at the mercy of the crunching beans, but that's it.  Add to this that the more the grinder weighs, or the more &quot;heft&quot; it has to it, the quieter it will typically be due to the additional mass damping any vibration.  When adding a motor to the mix, each step between the motor and the burrs adds an opportunity for noise.  As such, a direct drive grinder will typically be quieter than anything involving a gearbox.   &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The pecking order is basically...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hand Grinder --&gt; Direct Drive Flat Burr --&gt; Direct Drive Conical Burr --&gt; Gear-Reduced Burr&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While Decibel ratings are available from most manufacturers, they're difficult to translate into a subjective estimate of &quot;harshness.&quot;  I deal with these regularly and found that some of my favorite grinders are technically louder than several others, including the Baratza Vario. The difference is that they have a much more mellow drone rather than the gear motor's quieter whine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="26" LastEditorUserId="44" LastEditDate="2018-11-01T15:06:21.670" LastActivityDate="2018-11-01T15:06:21.670" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="58" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="165" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:41:45.373" Score="35" ViewCount="29280" Body="&lt;p&gt;I know a number of people have become fairly capable at getting a nice amount of crema at the end of the process of making a cup with their Aeropress.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I, however, am getting just a very thin, partial layer at best. I've experimented with pressure, and somewhat with water temperature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wondering if there's a magic bullet, or a good list of bullet points of things to do to maximize crema?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="68" LastEditorUserId="323" LastEditDate="2015-02-17T03:24:59.550" LastActivityDate="2022-11-14T09:51:34.160" Title="What's the most effective way of generating crema from an Aeropress?" Tags="&lt;aeropress&gt;&lt;crema&gt;" AnswerCount="7" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="59" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="44" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:42:44.507" Score="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;Coming from Germany myself I have seen this rating only on a single brand of coffee. There is no standard for this (even though us Germans seem to like standardizations), but basically strength of the coffee is about the inherent bitterness and caffeine content you get out of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The stonger a coffee the more caffeine and also the more bitterness you will usually get.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="46" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:42:44.507" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="60" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="61" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:49:00.850" Score="13" ViewCount="12806" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have visited Starbucks lots of times for their delicious coffee. As I stand in line, I hear people order coffee with like extra &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;shots&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried searching up what it means but to no avail.  Here's an example of what I hear people say:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;I would like some coffee with two extra shots please!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does the word &quot;shot&quot; mean in the coffee language? Yes, I have looked in the dictionary but no help was given.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="75" LastEditorUserId="56" LastEditDate="2017-06-27T02:41:56.190" LastActivityDate="2021-12-25T20:29:58.700" Title="What is a shot?" Tags="&lt;espresso&gt;&lt;terminology&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="61" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="60" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:53:45.747" Score="24" Body="&lt;p&gt;They are referring to a &amp;quot;shot&amp;quot; of espresso.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espresso#Brewing&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;Italian standards&lt;/a&gt; are that it is a volume of 25 mL  plus or minus ten percent.  Additional shots in a drink indicate more espresso flavor and a higher caffeine content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="76" LastEditorUserId="8287" LastEditDate="2021-04-12T09:09:34.457" LastActivityDate="2021-04-12T09:09:34.457" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="62" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="60" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:53:54.243" Score="9" Body="&lt;p&gt;A &quot;shot&quot; in this context usually means one ounce, or so, of espresso. So a cup of coffee with two extra shots would be a cup of coffee with approximately two ounces of espresso added.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T22:53:54.243" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="63" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="68" CreationDate="2015-01-27T22:54:44.590" Score="11" ViewCount="105998" Body="&lt;p&gt;I am often asked whether these three drinks have the same milk quantity and/or consistency and where the difference really lies between these preparations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I would assume that quantity is increased respectively (cortado &amp;lt; cappuccino &amp;lt; latte) but some claim that there is more milk in the cortado than the cappuccino.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the consistency, wouldn't the cappuccino have a more foamy milk than the other two?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="79" LastActivityDate="2018-02-17T21:23:51.787" Title="Milk quantity and consistency in cortado, cappuccino and latte" Tags="&lt;cappuccino&gt;&lt;latte&gt;&lt;milk&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="64" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="56" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:02:38.320" Score="16" Body="&lt;p&gt;It is possible to grow coffee indoors. If allowed to grow as a tree they can reach 8 feet tall but if trimmed occasionally you can get the plant to grow more like a bush around 3-4 feet. This will change some based on the exact type.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coffee plants prefer shade with a couple hours of direct sunlight in the morning. Keeping it by a window should be about right. Depending on your climate you want to be careful taking it outside during winter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As J Musser mentioned, this will be a long process that will yield very little, but it can be done.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the plus side, coffee plants are evergreens and look very nice as indoor plants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can read more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thanksgivingcoffee.com/blog/?p=174&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Edit: Stealing @JMussers comments to add to my answer&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;  &lt;p&gt;One large apartment plant will only produce enough coffee for a few cups worth each year, and that's after years of growth. They do look good, though. My point was, indoor coffee plants aren't that effective. Outdoors, a good plant will produce around 2-3 lbs. of grean beans per year. They are usually planted about 8'x8' apart, or a near equivalent, so 680 plants per acre, = around 1700 lbs of green coffee per acre per year, under good conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="23" LastEditorUserId="23" LastEditDate="2015-02-18T12:29:46.080" LastActivityDate="2015-02-18T12:29:46.080" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="66" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="181" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:09:27.093" Score="22" ViewCount="18077" Body="&lt;p&gt;I don't like coffees with an acidic/sour taste. However, when buying coffee, the only &quot;rating&quot; one gets is often how &quot;strong&quot; the coffee is, and that does not help me. Is there something else I can go on? Say, place of origin, or certain varieties that aren't acidic in taste?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="52" LastEditorUserId="47" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T08:05:00.223" LastActivityDate="2020-06-28T12:27:19.377" Title="What coffees are the least acidic?" Tags="&lt;flavor&gt;&lt;rating&gt;&lt;bean-varieties&gt;" AnswerCount="5" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="67" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="52" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:12:44.160" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;Body can sometimes also be described as &quot;mouth feel&quot;.  How &quot;heavy&quot; the coffee feels in ones mouth.  Roast darkness varies, of course, with the roast level.  However, body and acidity vary not only with roast level, but also with the variety of bean itself being roasted.  Different varieties of coffee will have varying different levels of body and acidity, which is further affected by the roast level applied to the beans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="76" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:12:44.160" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="68" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="63" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:18:14.363" Score="15" Body="&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There's a chart for that!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here's a &lt;a href=&quot;http://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0211/4926/files/PopChartLab__Expresso_Large506.jpg?1290&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to it, but I've also included an image below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There could be some argument over cappuccino vs. latte as to which is &quot;creamier&quot; as the cappuccino certainly has more mil foam, but the latte has much more milk by volume and by ratio. On the whole though I'd say the latte is a less strong drink with a creamier texture even if the cappuccino is thicker. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/PPKWM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;espresso based beverage chart&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="24" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:18:14.363" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="69" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="52" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:21:50.437" Score="3" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'm not really an expert, but in basic terms:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Roast darkness: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roughly how long was the coffee roasted, much like toast, a longer roast usually brings about a darker flavor. Darker roast coffees tend to have a slightly burnt caramelized flavor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Body:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I usually think of this as more of a texture than a flavor, probably more easily noticed at the extremes. A &quot;full bodied&quot; coffee sort of coats the tongue causing the flavor to linger while &quot;medium bodied&quot; coffees tend to be a little lighter with a cleaner finish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Acidity:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acidity is basically what it sounds like, lower acid coffees are often referred to as &quot;smooth&quot; and higher acid coffees referred to as &quot;bright&quot;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now &lt;a href=&quot;https://coffee.stackexchange.com/questions/52/roast-vs-body-vs-acidity#comment56_52&quot;&gt;as mentioned in the comments&lt;/a&gt; these terms are really painfully relative, and somewhat rendered meaningless by an onslaught of advertisers claiming that their coffee is &quot;smooth dark and full-bodied&quot; regardless of the real characteristics. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2017-04-13T12:51:53.733" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:21:50.437" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="70" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:22:28.207" Score="29" ViewCount="41541" Body="&lt;p&gt;Whenever I brew coffee with a French press, I tend to get a significant amount of grind left near the bottom of the cup, making the last bit of coffee far less enjoyable - mostly regardless, it seems, of how finely I grind the beans. Is there any method or tool I can use to minimize the amount of grind left at the bottom of the cup?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="user85" LastEditorUserId="5272" LastEditDate="2018-04-07T23:59:58.013" LastActivityDate="2019-03-09T14:56:50.693" Title="How can I minimize the amount of grounds at the bottom of my French press coffee?" Tags="&lt;french-press&gt;&lt;ground-coffee&gt;" AnswerCount="12" CommentCount="3" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="71" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="66" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:22:36.657" Score="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;I find that most of the Brazil dry processed coffee I get is very smooth or &quot;low acid&quot;.  However, in general coffees that are darker roasted will have less acid as the acids are destroyed in the roasting process.   You may look at the description as well.  Many of the fruit notes that some coffees advertise are coming from acid compounds that may overall contribute to an acidic feel of the coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="76" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:22:36.657" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="72" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="6" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:26:47.247" Score="22" Body="&lt;p&gt;The flavor and aroma of the beans continue to develop for the first few days after roasting as the beans release gas (this is the reason some retail coffee bags have valves to let the gases out). The process is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefreshloaf.com/node/11119/cooling-bread-how-long-wait&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;similar for bread&lt;/a&gt;, with some bakers preferring to let some types of bread rest longer than others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Right now I am actually drinking a cup of coffee made from beans I roasted this morning, because of poor planning. There's nothing wrong with it but I think it will be better in a couple of days. I find the aromatic qualities peak about 24-48 hours after roasting, but that may be because the off-gassing process is literally emitting the most fumes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;How the flavor changes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Subjectively, I'd say the smell and taste change like this:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During &lt;strong&gt;early roasting&lt;/strong&gt;, there are wood and vegetable smells, like when you put green wood on a fire and it puts out a lot of moisture-filled steam and begins to smoke.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Toward the &lt;strong&gt;end of the roast&lt;/strong&gt;, the smell is more from the browning/caramelization/Maillard reaction and smells kind of like burnt toast. Not really much like coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you grind and drink it &lt;strong&gt;immediately after roasting&lt;/strong&gt;, it tastes like generic coffee,  with those toasty flavors foreground. Very simple and straightforward without a lot of nuance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After 24 hours&lt;/strong&gt; the toasted character has diminished and the nuances have developed a lot more. You can really notice the difference between bean origins. There is much more powerful rich &quot;amazing coffee&quot; aroma. I find the sheer quantity of aroma very appealing at 24-48 hours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some beans continue to change for &lt;strong&gt;several days after roasting&lt;/strong&gt;. Recently I had a batch of Indonesian beans that were still developing and becoming more characteristically Indonesian after a week. I liked them more, but someone else might have liked them less.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And that, when it comes down to it, is what matters. Some people find some varieties more interesting, more palatable or less harsh as they age. But &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/De_gustibus_non_est_disputandum&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;de gustibus non est disputandum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It's amazing the human nose and tongue can sense these differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2&gt;See also&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecoffeefaq.com/5homeroasting.html#degassing&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&quot;Degassing, resting, and storage&quot; at thecoffeefaq.com&lt;/a&gt;, recommending at least 24 hours&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sweet Maria's claims coffee is &lt;a href=&quot;http://legacy.sweetmarias.com/freshroast.tipsheet.html&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&quot;at its flavor peak at 12-72 hours&quot;&lt;/a&gt; and recommends a &lt;a href=&quot;http://legacy.sweetmarias.com/roastedcoffeestorage.php&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;minimum 12-24 hour rest period&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;forums like home-barista.com report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/#q=resting+coffee+site:www.home-barista.com&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;much variation on preferred resting time.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="86" LastEditorUserId="86" LastEditDate="2016-09-13T22:22:19.353" LastActivityDate="2016-09-13T22:22:19.353" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="73" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="70" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:39:08.203" Score="5" Body="&lt;p&gt;It sounds like you may be grinding the coffee a little too fine or your press may be bent out of shape. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With a french press the grounds shouldn't pass through or around the screen, if they are make sure the screen is touching the sides of the cylinder all the way around and try a slightly courser grind. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:39:08.203" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="75" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:48:13.630" Score="2" ViewCount="86" Body="&lt;p&gt;I know that coffee in a coffee machine is usually prepared using a temperature between 91–94 °C. Some people say 85°C is ideal. The pressure is usually between 8 and 18 bars.&#xA;My questions are specifically, what are ideal/recommended temperatures for different brewing methods:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;instant coffee&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;french press&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;moka pot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;drip brew&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and so on ...&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="90" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:48:13.630" Title="What is/are the ideal brewing temperature(s) when preparing coffee?" Tags="&lt;temperature&gt;" AnswerCount="0" CommentCount="1" ClosedDate="2015-01-28T15:43:06.907" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="76" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="70" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:51:12.140" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;Are you using a burr grinder or a blade grinder? Blade grinders physically cannot give a consistent grind; you'll always have some too-fine (and some too-coarse) bits of beans. If you're having the beans ground where you buy them, have them done as coarse as the grinder will go and see if that helps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can also try replacing the screen in your press. (Bodum sells replacement screens online.) If the wires at the edges are bent, they could be letting grounds through.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you don't mind branching out a little, I've become a devoted fan of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.gamilacompany.com/impress/features/&quot;&gt;Impress brewer&lt;/a&gt; from Gamila. (The link goes to the features page.) It works the same way as a french press, but the apertures in the filter are closer to the size of an espresso machine's filter (roughly 0.2 mm), rather than the +/- 1mm in a traditional french press screen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="91" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:51:12.140" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="77" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="54" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:51:43.470" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Stirring should be used if the grounds were not evenly dispersed in the beginning of the process for some reason (in immersion brewing methods).  For instance, when I am using my pour over at work, if my initial pour leaves some dry spots floating on top.  The Aeropress uses stirring prior to extraction presumably because the short time combined with the tube shape (narrow with all the grounds at the bottom) demand a good mixing.  I've seen many badly designed drip brewers that leave a chunk of dry grounds in the basket when done.  This is because the drip isn't dispersing water evenly and some of the grounds end up wasted,  finer grind, longer brew and temp won't necessarily help bad engineering in that case.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="76" LastActivityDate="2015-01-27T23:51:43.470" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="78" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="121" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:53:26.760" Score="14" ViewCount="65854" Body="&lt;p&gt;Most moka pots don't work on my induction stove. How can I still use them? &#xA;I use a camping stove temporarily, but it requires me to buy gas refills every now and then. Is there an easier way?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="90" LastEditorUserId="127" LastEditDate="2015-02-06T14:00:23.407" LastActivityDate="2020-09-07T21:23:12.600" Title="Most moka pots don't work on my induction stove. How can I still use them?" Tags="&lt;brewing-process&gt;&lt;moka&gt;&lt;induction&gt;" AnswerCount="9" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="79" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="324" CreationDate="2015-01-27T23:53:51.513" Score="68" ViewCount="205712" Body="&lt;p&gt;I haven't been able to find a good way to approximate the amount of caffeine in the coffee I make. Googling yields information like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mayoclinic.org/healthy-living/nutrition-and-healthy-eating/in-depth/caffeine/art-20049372&quot;&gt;this Mayo Clinic article&lt;/a&gt; that mixes serving sizes and brewing methods, and it reports one 8 oz coffee contains &quot;95-200 mg&quot; of caffeine, which is a huge range. If I have three cups of coffee in a day, is that 300 or 600 mg of caffeine?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are so many variables in prepared coffee, different extraction methods, beans, roasts, serving sizes, mixed with different amounts of water or milk. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is there a general method for calculating the caffeine in prepared coffee?&lt;/strong&gt; Something like &quot;most brewing methods extract &lt;em&gt;X&lt;/em&gt; mg of caffeine from each &lt;em&gt;Y&lt;/em&gt; grams of ground coffee&quot;?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Or more specifically, what method would I use to accurately estimate how much caffeine is in an 8oz serving from my 10 oz french press, made with medium- (not course-) ground medium-roast arabica beans, brewed 4 minutes before decanting?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="86" LastActivityDate="2022-11-24T16:18:35.037" Title="How can I figure out how much caffeine is in my cup?" Tags="&lt;brewing-process&gt;&lt;caffeine&gt;" AnswerCount="8" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="80" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="53" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:13:05.467" Score="8" Body="&lt;p&gt;That sounds like the generalization that drip or pour over brewing is better for light roasts and stronger brewing methods are better for darker roasts.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I'll counter that by saying that I often use my Aeropress for lighter roasts and my Clever Dripper for dark roasts and those cups come out just fine.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Aeropress makes a sort of quasi-espresso cup that isn't true espresso, but is much stronger than just strong coffee.  I've found that it is unsuitable or less than satisfactory for beans that aren't recommended for espresso brewing.  While the Aeropress allows less control over &quot;brew&quot; strength.  The V60 should be more flexible.  Varying the grind and pour speed should allow a level of control not present with an Aeropress.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="76" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T00:13:05.467" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="81" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="90" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:13:43.660" Score="39" ViewCount="85766" Body="&lt;p&gt;I was wondering why single serving coffee &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/sachet&quot;&gt;sachets&lt;/a&gt; never really took off the way tea bags have. The only explanation I could find was that steeping coffee too long makes the coffee taste bad, but it seems like that could be avoided by removing the bag.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why would the end result be terribly different than a french press, Turkish brew, or cowboy coffee? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="31" LastEditorUserId="86" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T00:53:02.853" LastActivityDate="2019-01-23T14:03:16.113" Title="Why isn't coffee commonly sold in sachets, like tea bags?" Tags="&lt;brewing-process&gt;&lt;single-serving&gt;" AnswerCount="10" CommentCount="6" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="82" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="66" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:23:36.533" Score="13" Body="&lt;p&gt;Sumatran coffees (and others from the Asia/Pacific region, like Java and Arabia) are uniformly low-acid. As @Chris said, the processing methods and roast have a lot to do with it. Coffees that have been dry- (or &quot;natural&quot; processed) are lower in acids than washed-process coffees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often, acidic coffee is described as being &quot;bright&quot; (e.g., Starbucks Colombia). You can spot the ones that will be lower in acid when the description uses terms like earthy, spicy, or smooth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="91" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T00:23:36.533" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="84" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:29:53.437" Score="15" ViewCount="9649" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a grinding machine with a lot of different settings. Even between the categories of Fine and Medium there are sub levels of grinding. I'm not sure how they relate to the flavor of the coffee. Is there any research that shows how the grind affects the taste of the different types of roasts?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/lsio9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="95" LastEditorUserId="6506" LastEditDate="2019-05-22T11:09:46.310" LastActivityDate="2021-05-13T19:58:23.770" Title="How does coffee grind size affect coffee taste" Tags="&lt;flavor&gt;&lt;grinder&gt;" AnswerCount="4" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="85" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="70" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:37:01.953" Score="27" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have the same problem, and these things definitely reduce it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grind more coarsely. Blade grinders are incapable of really doing this—they give you boulders and powder. But I've never been satisfied with the taste when I use coarse grounds— it's weak and lacks body.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make sure the screen fits well and no grounds are squirting along the sides&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Press gently, don't force it down with a lot of pressure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After pressing, wait a minute before decanting&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Don't drink the dregs remaining at the bottom of the cup... unless you're like a friend of mine who relishes them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if none of that works for you, try a different brew method. Paper filters are very good at keeping grounds out of your cup.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="86" LastEditorUserId="86" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T22:21:36.213" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T22:21:36.213" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="86" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="81" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:46:41.187" Score="16" Body="&lt;p&gt;Because coffee is an agricultural/baked item and like bread, goes stale.  Between roasting, grinding packaging and shipping the bags, you'd ensure the coffee was never fresh and will never taste good.  The most you may get is a mass produced cup of horrible that might be passable or better than nothing to a small percentage of people.  &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The other brew methods you list are generally used by people buying fresher, specialty coffee from shops.  Those methods are all a bit more intensive and tend to be used by people a bit more picky that folks buying Folgers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="76" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T00:46:41.187" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="87" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="84" CreationDate="2015-01-28T00:53:41.237" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;The main reason for different grinds is the different brewing processes. If the water is exposed to the grounds for a very short amount of time (e.g., 10-15 seconds for espresso), you need a finer grind to provide enough surface area to extract the coffee from the beans. If the brewing time is long (e.g., the ~4 minutes of french press), you need a coarse grind to avoid over-extracting the grounds and getting something too bitter to drink.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That's really the heart of it. If the grind is too coarse for your brewing method, your coffee will end up under-extracted, weak, and acidic. If it is too fine a grind, your coffee ends up over-extracted and bitter. Your grinder is a good brand; if you still have the manual, it includes a guide to grind vs. brewing method. If not, the capresso.com site includes PDF versions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="91" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T00:53:41.237" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="88" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="79" CreationDate="2015-01-28T01:12:16.993" Score="14" Body="&lt;p&gt;Well I am not sure how thay did it but here is the website about the amount of caffeine there is in certain cups of coffee (types will vary): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.caffeineinformer.com/the-caffeine-database&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;Caffeine In Coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There will be caffeine intake of other drinks as well.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Well here is another website where it explains the amount of coffee per type (not brands). It was made by ICO, the International Coffee Organization: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ico.org/caffeine.asp&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://www.ico.org/caffeine.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="75" LastEditorUserId="-1" LastEditDate="2020-06-18T08:36:22.093" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T01:59:24.847" CommentCount="6" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="89" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="112" CreationDate="2015-01-28T01:15:44.047" Score="6" ViewCount="252" Body="&lt;p&gt;In what way does the altitude at which coffee beans are grown affect the flavor of the final roast?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I often see coffees labeled with marketing materials such as &quot;contains only beans grown above x thousand feet.&quot; Does the altitude at which the beans are grown actually affect the final flavor of the coffee? If so, what are the mechanisms which cause this, and what does it do to the actual flavor of the final product?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerDisplayName="user80" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T08:23:14.633" Title="How does the altitude at which beans are grown affect the final roast?" Tags="&lt;beans&gt;&lt;growing&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="4" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="90" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="81" CreationDate="2015-01-28T01:33:09.917" Score="28" Body="&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, coffee is &quot;commonly&quot; sold in some kind of sachets.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Japan, there is what is called &quot;one-drip bag coffee&quot;. It consists of a flat sachet that you can unfold to deploy a small scaffold. The scaffold adapts to any mug-like cups. It unveils a filter containing ground coffee, as it unfolds. You just need to pour hot water in the filter to get a decent cup of coffee.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I will not link to any maker or brand, but most coffee dealers in Japan offer these bags---pretty convenient and offering a decent cup for the price. These bags seem somewhat popular in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am not sure about global availability, though. Several countries do not sell them (e.g. Europe, perhaps because of the French / Italian influences).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/wXDRs.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/wXDRs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanging Ear Drip Coffee Filter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/0GhXu.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/0GhXu.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drip Type Portable Coffee Paper Filter&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="98" LastEditorUserId="7383" LastEditDate="2019-01-23T14:03:16.113" LastActivityDate="2019-01-23T14:03:16.113" CommentCount="13" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 4.0" />
  <row Id="91" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="28" CreationDate="2015-01-28T02:13:33.510" Score="4" Body="&lt;p&gt;Most high-end automatic grinders allow you to adjust for coarseness, not speed, as they're driven by a gear box that makes them operate consistently. This is important, because consistency allows you to produce exactly the same cup that you did previously by simply reproducing the grind / tamping / temp / etc. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you drink exotic beans, such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.botecentral.net/coffee-alamid-the-worlds-rarest-brew/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;alamid&lt;/a&gt;, then you &lt;em&gt;probably&lt;/em&gt; want to also purchase a hand (crank) powered burr grinder as some beans are particularly sensitive to the heat that can be produced by the grinding process itself. While ceramic burr grinders do very well at minimizing heat, it's nice to have a hand grinder for when you want full control.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Breville &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brevilleusa.com/the-smart-grinder.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;smart grinder&lt;/a&gt; is a very good grinder for home use at a just above entry-level price. All the control you want, easy to use, extremely consistent and handles baskets or portafilters of either size.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For a hand grinder, I'm quite fond of my antique steel burr grinder: &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/msRSXm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old but reliable&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I can grind enough for a double shot in about 30 - 45 seconds, the top knob adjusts for coarseness while how fast I move my arm controls the amount of heat I produce just grinding the beans :)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don't use blade grinders because you have no real control over &lt;em&gt;either&lt;/em&gt; - they tend to get too hot &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; they produce inconsistent grinds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="101" LastEditorUserId="37" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T02:58:36.360" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T02:58:36.360" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="92" PostTypeId="2" ParentId="44" CreationDate="2015-01-28T02:54:46.753" Score="2" Body="&lt;p&gt;The Starbucks-owned brand &quot;Seattle's Best Coffee&quot; uses numbers on its bagged supermarket coffees, too. I equate it to the stars you can use to order Asian takeout with more or less spiciness. There's no set scale I've ever found, but it's a general way to tell the consumer where on the spectrum each product (roughly) lies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="91" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T02:54:46.753" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="93" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="205" CreationDate="2015-01-28T03:12:46.843" Score="14" ViewCount="3626" Body="&lt;p&gt;I've noticed the water pressure from espresso machines varies from about 12 psi to 22 psi. What effect does this have on flavor? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="101" LastEditDate="2015-01-29T04:23:49.310" LastActivityDate="2016-08-10T17:58:40.647" Title="How does pressure affect the flavor of espresso?" Tags="&lt;espresso&gt;&lt;flavor&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="94" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="103" CreationDate="2015-01-28T03:15:34.813" Score="16" ViewCount="67872" Body="&lt;p&gt;Many people seem to think that a 0.85oz shot of espresso has the same amount of caffeine as a cup of coffee. Is there any validity to this?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="76" LastEditDate="2015-02-20T16:15:48.713" LastActivityDate="2016-12-21T22:15:18.743" Title="How much caffeine is in an espresso shot?" Tags="&lt;espresso&gt;&lt;caffeine&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="95" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="175" CreationDate="2015-01-28T03:19:40.670" Score="6" ViewCount="4306" Body="&lt;p&gt;What is the correct amount of milk to put into a macchiato? Does it depend on the amount of espresso? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="16" LastEditDate="2015-01-28T17:41:59.257" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T18:28:30.810" Title="Amount of milk in a macchiato beverage" Tags="&lt;espresso&gt;&lt;milk&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="96" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="194" CreationDate="2015-01-28T03:25:30.270" Score="42" ViewCount="2331" Body="&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, what do &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold_brew&quot;&gt;cold brewed&lt;/a&gt;&quot; methods hope to achieve compared to the more traditional hot-water methods of extraction? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Does the amount of caffeine vary between hot brewed and cold brewed coffee?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What about the other compounds such as Salicylic acid, phenolic acids, and amino acids? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="5272" LastEditDate="2018-04-07T23:59:20.743" LastActivityDate="2018-04-07T23:59:20.743" Title="How will &quot;cold brewed&quot; coffee differ from traditional hot-water extraction methods?" Tags="&lt;cold-brew&gt;&lt;extraction&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="5" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="97" PostTypeId="1" CreationDate="2015-01-28T03:29:13.230" Score="15" ViewCount="19713" Body="&lt;p&gt;I have a stove top percolator for making espresso.  It does not generate any crema.  it possible to do so with a stove top percolator? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="127" LastEditDate="2015-02-10T15:28:29.793" LastActivityDate="2019-01-03T09:09:04.123" Title="Generating crema with a moka pot?" Tags="&lt;crema&gt;&lt;moka&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="2" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="98" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="407" CreationDate="2015-01-28T03:45:57.007" Score="16" ViewCount="9780" Body="&lt;p&gt;Standard and V60 paper filters require we fold the border before spreading them for dripping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe this is just because of their manufacturing process. But would there be any other reason?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Folding that border makes the surface uneven in the end, and it can sometimes be harder to control the water flow.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/R6Tms.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Folded border on a V60 filter&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="98" LastEditorUserId="98" LastEditDate="2015-02-11T13:15:06.647" LastActivityDate="2021-07-03T18:34:49.770" Title="Why do we need to fold the border of filters?" Tags="&lt;filter&gt;&lt;drip-brew&gt;" AnswerCount="3" CommentCount="7" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="99" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="102" CreationDate="2015-01-28T04:14:05.120" Score="21" ViewCount="1575" Body="&lt;p&gt;Does storing ground coffee in a freezer make it stay fresh longer? If so, how long will it remain fresh? &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="110" LastEditorUserId="5272" LastEditDate="2018-04-07T23:59:53.720" LastActivityDate="2018-04-07T23:59:53.720" Title="Does storing coffee in a freezer preserve freshness?" Tags="&lt;storage&gt;&lt;freshness&gt;" AnswerCount="2" CommentCount="1" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
  <row Id="100" PostTypeId="1" AcceptedAnswerId="105" CreationDate="2015-01-28T04:37:55.437" Score="8" ViewCount="649" Body="&lt;p&gt;I'll have a chance to visit some coffee farms in the coming months, at which time I'll be able to purchase small amounts of 'green' Arabica beans. The only experience I have with purchasing these types of beans in the past has been online, and I'm not particularly certain that the beans I received could be considered fresh.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a chance to actually see what I'm getting before I get it, what should I look for in a fresh bean as far as quality? Are there characteristics that I can look for which indicate that (if properly roasted) the bean will produce something good? I can only compare with what I've bought previously, which was of dubious quality, so I'm not entirely sure what to look for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;" OwnerUserId="101" LastActivityDate="2015-01-28T07:08:49.517" Title="How do I judge the quality of 'green' beans?" Tags="&lt;whole-bean&gt;&lt;arabica&gt;" AnswerCount="1" CommentCount="0" ContentLicense="CC BY-SA 3.0" />
</posts>